The path to paradise begins in hell.
Alien: Covenant is a horror, science fiction,
thriller film directed by Ridley Scott.
The crew of the colony ship Covenant, bound for a remote planet on the far side of the galaxy,
discovers what they think is an uncharted paradise but is actually a dark, dangerous world.
David / Walter, played by Michael Fassbender.
Daniels, played by Katherine Waterston.
Oram, played by Billy Crudup.
Tennessee, played by Danny McBride.
Lope, played by Demián Bichir.
Karine, played by Carmen Ejogo.
Alien: Covenant is a 2017  science fiction horror film directed and co-produced by Ridley Scott from a
screenplay by John Logan and Dante Harper, based on a story by Michael Green and Jack Paglen.
It is the sixth installment in the Alien film series
and the sequel to Prometheus (2012).
It features returning star Michael Fassbender, with Katherine Waterston, Billy
Crudup, Danny McBride, and Demián Bichir in supporting roles.
It follows the crew of a colony ship that lands on an
uncharted planet and makes a terrifying discovery.
In 2012, before the release of Prometheus, Scott discussed the prospects of a
sequel and new trilogy, and this film was confirmed that August.
Principal photography began on April 4, 2016, at Milford Sound in Fiordland
National Park, New Zealand, and wrapped on July 19, 2016.
Effects houses Odd Studios and CreatureNFX provided the
film's makeup and animatronic creature effects.
Scott said the film's first cut was 2 hours and 23 minutes,
which was edited down by over twenty minutes.
Alien: Covenant premiered in London on May 4, 2017.
It was released by 20th Century Fox on May 12 in the United
Kingdom, and on May 19 in the United States.
It received generally positive reviews from critics but was considered a box office
disappointment, grossing $240 million against a production budget of $97–111 million.
The film explores themes of android, spacecraft,
experiment, space travel, infection.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.